<resources>
    <string name="app_name">30 Day Core Workout</string>
    <string name="expand_button_content_description">View Instructions</string>
    <string name="how_to_do_exercise">How to do the exercise?</string>
    <string name="duration_format">Duration: %d seconds</string>
    <string name="one_set_format">One Set: %d reps</string>
    <!--Exercises-->
    <string name="bird_dog">Bird Dog</string>
    <string name="bear_plank">Bear Plank</string>
    <string name="plank_shoulder_tap">Plank Shoulder Tap</string>
    <string name="mountain_climbers">Mountain Climbers</string>
    <string name="leg_raises">Leg Raises</string>
    <string name="v_hold">V Hold</string>
    <string name="toe_touches">Toe Touches</string>
    <string name="plank_up_downs">Plank Up Downs</string>
    <string name="dead_bug">Dead Bug</string>
    <string name="scissors">Scissors</string>
    <string name="russian_twists">Russian Twists</string>
    <string name="side_plank">Side Plank</string>
    <string name="glute_bridge">Glute Bridge</string>
    <string name="spiderman_crunches">Spiderman Crunches</string>
    <string name="heel_touches">Heel Touches</string>
    <string name="windshield_wipers">Windshield Wipers</string>
    <string name="reverse_crunches">Reverse Crunches</string>
    <string name="criss_cross_flutter_kicks">Criss Cross Flutter Kicks</string>
    <string name="superman">Superman</string>
    <string name="burpees">Burpees</string>
    <string name="high_knees">High Knees</string>
    <string name="sliding_pike">Sliding Pike</string>
    <string name="seated_knee_tucks">Seated Knee Tucks</string>
    <string name="high_plank">High Planks</string>
    <string name="standing_criss_cross_crunch">Standing Criss Cross Crunch</string>
    <string name="wood_chop">Wood Chop</string>
    <string name="hollow_body_hold">Hollow Body Hold</string>
    <string name="rolling_plank">Rolling Plank</string>
    <string name="breakdance">Breakdance</string>
    <string name="seagull">Seagull</string>
    <!--Instructions-->
    <string name="bird_dog_instructions">
        1. Get into a tabletop position with your shoulders directly over your wrists and your hips
        in line with your knees.
        \n\n2. Keeping your right foot flexed, straighten your leg behind you as you extend your
        left hand out in front of you.
    </string>
    <string name="bear_plank_instructions">
        1. Get into a tabletop position with your shoulders directly over your hands and your hips
        in line with your knees.
        \n\n2. Tightening your core and glutes, lift your knees an inch or two off the ground and
        hold for 30 seconds while maintaining a flat back.
        \n\n3. Once you are able to hold this position for 30 seconds, add another 15 seconds.
    </string>
    <string name="plank_shoulder_tap_instructions">
        1. From a tabletop position with your hands directly underneath your shoulders and your hips
        in line with your hips, lift your knees an inch or two off the ground.
        \n\n2. Now, lift your right hand off the ground to tap your left shoulder.
        \n\n3. Bring your hand back down and lift your left hand to tap your right shoulder.
    </string>
    <string name="mountain_climbers_instructions">
        1. Starting in a high plank position, lift your left foot to bend your left knee and tap
        your right elbow.
        \n\n2. Then, bring it back to plank.
        \n\n3. Next, lift your right foot to bend your right knee and bring it toward your left
        elbow to tap it.
    </string>
    <string name="leg_raises_instructions">
        1. On a yoga mat, lie face up and bring your legs together.
        \n\n2. Lower your feet toward the ground without touching it.
        \n\n3. Hold it for a second and then bring your legs back up.
    </string>
    <string name="v_hold_instructions">
        1. Lie face up on a yoga mat with your legs extended in front of you and your hands behind
        your head.
        \n\n2. Lift your arms by your ears and your neck and shoulders off the ground. At the
        same time, your legs and feet off the ground.
        \n\n3. Hold this position for 30 seconds, working your way up to a full minute.
    </string>
    <string name="toe_touches_instructions">
        1. Lie face up on a yoga mat and hold your legs straight up in the air.
        \n\n2. Straighten your arms pointing upwards and attempt to reach up toward your toes.
    </string>
    <string name="plank_up_downs_instructions">
        1. Start in a table-top position on the floor with hands stacked directly under shoulders,
        knees bent and stacked directly under hips, and feet hip-width apart.
        \n\n2. Lift both knees off the floor and straighten legs to come into a high plank position
        on palms, squeezing glutes together and engaging core.
        \n\n3. Actively push away from the floor and maintain a straight line from head to heels.
        \n\n4. This is the starting position.
        \n\n5. Keeping hips square, lower right elbow to the floor, then left elbow, to come into a
        forearm plank. Place right hand under right shoulder, then left hand under left shoulder to
        return to a high plank.
        \n\n6. Repeat the plank up-down with the left side leading, lowering left elbow to the floor,
        then right elbow, to come into a forearm plank.
        \n\n7. Place left hand under left shoulder, then right hand under right shoulder to return
        to a high plank.
    </string>
    <string name="dead_bug_instructions">
        1. Lie on back with legs in a table-top position, calves parallel to the floor, arms
        extended up toward the ceiling.
        \n\n2. Extend one arm back and the opposite leg down, hovering an inch off the ground, then
        return and switch sides.
    </string>
    <string name="scissors_instructions">
        1. Lie on back, hands under butt for support and legs extended straight on the floor.
        \n\n2. Lift right leg up to point toward the ceiling.
        \n\n3. While lowering right leg, raise left leg to point to the ceiling.
    </string>
    <string name="russian_twists_instructions">
        1. Sit with sacrum on the floor, legs up in tabletop position and back off the floor, hands
        in prayer.
        \n\n2. Twist to the right, tapping right elbow to the floor.
        \n\n3. Twist to the left, tapping left elbow to the floor.
        \n\n4. Repeat each rep by alternating sides.
    </string>
    <string name="side_plank_instructions">
        1. Lie on your right side, legs extended and stacked from hip to feet.
        \n\n2. The elbow of your right arm is directly under your shoulder.
        \n\n3. Ensure your head is directly in line with your spine.
        \n\n4. Your left arm can be aligned along the left side of your body.
    </string>
    <string name="glute_bridge_instructions">
        1. Begin on your back with your knees bent, arms straight beside you, feet flat on the ground.
        \n\n2. Your fingertips should barely be able to touch your heels.
        \n\n3. Engage your core.
        \n\n4. Press into your heels to lift your hips up until your body is a straight line between
        your knees and your shoulders.
        \n\n5. Hold for two seconds and slowly return to the starting
        position.
        \n\n6. Repeat for one minute.
    </string>
    <string name="spiderman_crunches_instructions">
        1. Get into a high plank position with your shoulders directly over your wrists.
        \n\n2. Lift your left foot to bend your bend knee and bring it towards your left elbow.
        \n\n3. Tap your left elbow if you can, tightening your left oblique.
        \n\n4. Then, bring your left foot back to the starting position.
        \n\n5. Next, lift your right foot to bend your right knee and bring it towards your
        right elbow, tightening your right oblique.
        \n\n6. Bring your right foot back to the starting position.
        \n\n7. Repeat steps 1 to 6 to complete subsequent reps.
    </string>
    <string name="heel_touches_instructions">
        1. Lie face up on a yoga mat with your arms by your sides and your feet flat on the ground.
        \n\n2. Keep your heels close to your butt.
        \n\n3. Lift your neck and shoulders off the ground and reach your hands to tap the heels of
        your feet.
    </string>
    <string name="windshield_wipers_instructions">
        1. Lie on your back facing upwards. Bend your knees such that your feet is resting flat on
        the floor and extend your arms to either side.
        \n\n2. In this position, raise your legs such that your thighs are perpendicular to the
        floor with your knees in the air. Make sure your lower back is pressed into the floor.
        \n\n3. Move your hips around to find a comfortable position. This is the starting position.
        \n\n4. Keeping your shoulder blades pressed firmly to the floor, engage your core and twist
        your spine to drop your knees to the left side of your body.
        \n\n5. Afterwards, return back to the starting position and drop your knees to the right
        side of your body.
        \n\n6. Finally return back to the starting position to complete one rep.
    </string>
    <string name="reverse_crunches_instructions">
        1. Lie face up on a mat or other soft surface with your knees bent at 90 degrees and your
        feet flat on the floor.
        \n\n2. Keep your arms near your sides with your palms down.
        \n\n3. Exhale and brace your core.
        \n\n4. Lift your feet off the ground and raise your thighs until they’re vertical.
        \n\n5. Keep your knees bent at 90 degrees throughout the movement.
        \n\n6. Tuck your knees toward your face as far as you can comfortably go without lifting
        your mid-back from the mat. Your hips and lower back should lift off the ground.
        \n\n7. Hold for a moment and slowly lower your feet back toward the floor until they reach
        the ground.
    </string>
    <string name="criss_cross_flutter_kicks_instructions">
        1. Lie down on your back, facing up.
        \n\n2. Place both hands underneath your buttocks.
        \n\n3. Keep your lower back on the ground as you lift both legs up, slightly past hip height,
        keeping your core engaged the entire time.
        \n\n4. Criss cross your legs over one another, switching off which leg is on top, and keeping
        your legs off the ground the entire time.
        \n\n5. For more of a challenge, lift your head and neck off the floor. The wider you bring
        out your legs with each cross, the more you’ll feel the exercise in your abs.
    </string>
    <string name="superman_instructions">
        1. Lie on your stomach with a rolled towel or a small pillow under your hips to support your
        \n\n2. back. You might also use a folded towel to support your head.
        \n\n3. Tighten your abdominal muscles.
        \n\n4. Raise your right arm off the floor (A). Hold for three deep breaths.
        \n\n5. Lower your right arm and repeat with your left arm.
        \n\n6. Raise your right leg off the floor (B). Hold for three deep breaths.
        \n\n7. Lower your right leg and repeat with your left leg.
    </string>
    <string name="burpees_instructions">
        1. Squat down and place your hands flat on the floor in front of your feet and shoulder-width
        apart.
        \n\n2. Squat thrust. Jump both feet out and back to land in the pushup position.
        \n\n3. Push-up. Bend your arms and lower your chest to lightly touch the floor. Push back up to
        full arm extension
        \n\n4. Squat. Jump both feet back in and under your body, knees close to your elbows
        \n\n5. Jump. Leap up into the air as high as you can. Land on slightly bent knees.
    </string>
    <string name="high_knees_instructions">
        1. Stand straight with your feet shoulder-width apart.
        \n\n2. Face forward and open your chest.
        \n\n3. Bring your knees up to waist level and then slowly land on the balls of your feet.
        \n\n4. Repeat until the set is complete.
    </string>
    <string name="sliding_pike_instructions">
        1. While seated on your mat, extend your legs fully straight out in front and lean backwards
        keeping spine neutral (tip: do not round your back).
        \n\n2. Next, with your legs extended, start to bend your legs, bringing your knees towards
        your chest.
        \n\n3. With your knees bent, hold the position for a second or two, then extend your legs
        outwards and return to the starting position without touching the mat.
        \n\n4. Repeat steps 1 to 3 for each subsequent rep.
    </string>
    <string name="seated_knee_tucks_instructions">
        1. While seated on your mat, extend your legs fully straight out in front and lean backwards
        keeping spine neutral (tip: do not round your back).
        \n\n2. Next, with your legs extended, start to bend your legs, bringing your knees towards
        your chest.
        \n\n3. With your knees bent, hold the position for a second or two, then extend your legs
        outwards and return to the starting position without touching the mat.
        \n\n4. Repeat steps 1 to 3 for each subsequent rep.
    </string>
    <string name="high_plank_instructions">
        1. Get into an all-fours position hands shoulder-width apart and get yourself in a
        push-up position.
        \n\n2. Keep your legs hip-width apart or slightly wider.
        \n\n3. Pre-tension your shoulders and hips while engaging your core.
        \n\n4. Keep your ribs down and your pelvis slightly tucked.
        \n\n5. Squeeze your quads and glutes. Your chin should remain tucked throughout the movement,
        as if you were holding an egg under your chin.
        \n\n6. Continue to engage your core and maintain full-body tension. Hold for the desired length
        of time.
    </string>
    <string name="standing_criss_cross_crunch_instructions">
        1. Stand up straight with your feet hip-width apart and your hands behind your head.
        \n\n2. Bend your right leg and lift your knee as high as you can.
        \n\n3. Rotate your torso to the right and bring your right knee to your left elbow.
        \n\n4. Repeat on the opposite side and keep alternating sides until the set is complete
    </string>
    <string name="wood_chop_instructions">
        1. Stand with your feet wider than shoulder width apart, knees slightly bent.
        \n\n2. Hold the medicine ball in both hands and keep your arms straight.
        \n\n3. Rotating at your waist, explosively lift the ball up above your shoulder to the left.
        \n\n4. Control it at the top and bring the ball back down to waist height on your right.
        \n\n5. Perform all your reps on one side, then swap.
    </string>
    <string name="hollow_body_hold_instructions">
        1. Lie on your back and extend your arms overhead.
        \n\n2. Straighten your legs with your feet together and toes pointed.
        \n\n3. From there, tighten your core by drawing your ribs toward your pelvis and flexing your
        abdominal region.
        \n\n4. Then raise your feet, legs, and shoulders off of the ground and flatten your lower back
        against the floor
    </string>
    <string name="rolling_plank_instructions">
        1. Start in forward plank position. (Position A)
        \n\n2. Turn your body to right side plank position. (Position B)
        \n\n3. Return to forward plank position (Position A)
        \n\n4. Turn your body to left side plank position. (Position C)
        \n\n5. Return to forward plank position (Position A)
        \n\n6. Repeat steps 1 to 5 for subsequent reps.
    </string>
    <string name="breakdance_instructions">
        1. Get down on your hands and knees and lift your knees a few inches off the floor.
        \n\n2. Lift your left hand and your right foot off the floor, rotate your hips to the left,
        place your left heel on the floor, and kick your right leg to the left.
        \n\n3. Rotate your hips to the right and return to the starting position.
        \n\n4. Switch sides and repeat.
    </string>
    <string name="seagull_instructions">
        1. Get yourself to forward plank position.
        \n\n2. Lift your left hand till its straight and parallel to the ground.
        \n\n3. Swipe your left hand and rotate 90 degrees to the left.
        \n\n4. Return your left hand to forward plank position.
        \n\n5. Lift your right hand till its straight and parallel to the ground.
        \n\n6. Swipe your right hand and rotate 90 degrees to the right.
        \n\n7. Return your right hand to forward plank position.
        \n\n8. Repeat steps 1 to 7 for subsequent reps.
    </string>
</resources>